Rustamjon Khuseinov

Frontend Software Engineer

in linkedin.com/in/khuseinov

Experienced software engineer specializing in front-end development with a passion for creating outstanding web applications. I approach my work responsibly. I take care of my physical and spiritual health and actively invest in my education.

Experience

Aug 2022 - present Moskow, Russia

Frontend Developer at My Facets (Remote)

- Conducted a successful project migration process from using a standard HTML, CSS and JavaScript to more modern technologies, including TypeScript, React and styled components.
- Multilingual support using i18n.
- Code coverage with tests (Jest + React Testing Library).
- Improved the code-style on the project, which significantly reduced the code-review time.

Jan 2021 - Aug 2022 Tel Aviv. Israel

Frontend Developer at Sosivio (Remote)

- Development of Dashboard in React + TypeScript in collaboration with Al and backend
- Improved SEO optimization, eliminating many bugs and increasing quality user experience.
- Creation of a scalable and reliable code base with 65%+ test coverage
- Development and support of a UI-Kit consisting of reusable components to standardize the interface and speed up development.

May 2020 - Jan 2021

Tomsk, Russia

Frontend Developer at Crypton Studio (Remote)

- Was one of the first developers who actively influenced the implementation and

using React when it first came to the company.

- Optimized Git flow, making it more efficient and relevant to needs project.
- Improved the code-style of projects, expanding the ESLint and prettier configuration with my own rules, increasing the level of code quality and reducing the number of errors.
- Participated in cross-code reviews, task estimation and sprint planning

Education

2018 - 2023 **Bachelor's Degree in Tourism**

Kazan, Russia Kazan National Research Technological University 🗹

2016 - 2018 **Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science**

Kazan, Russia Kazan Federal University 🛮

Skills

Front-end development

TypeScript, JavaScript(ES6+), React, Redux (Thunk, Toolkit), HTML, CSS, SCSS/Sass, Styled-Components, Framer-Motion, Tailwind, Webpack, Vite, Parcel, Jest, RTL.

Back-end development

Node.js (Express)

Tools & Platforms

Git, GitHub, Figma, Photoshop, Postman, Jira, Trello, Vercel, Netlify, Docker, Jira, Trello, Postman.

Languages

English Russian Uzbek Tajik German Persian